Kumarraja ArumugamKrishnasamy

ak.kumar.raja@gmail.com

8563168510

Plainsboro, NJ, 08536, United States

Profile

Accomplished Professional with 15+ years of experience in Technical Program and Product Management, Large Application Integration/Implementations. Expert in Product development, Agile, and Business/Digital transformation. Strong expertise in migrating legacy monolith applications in Microservices, Data Transformation, and Application Migration.

Experience in delivering highly visible projects from conception to implementation. Knowledgeable in SAFe (Scaled Agile) Portfolio practices including Value Streams. A unique blend of technical consulting expertise and management skills. Strong technical skills and full life cycle experience in Core Banking, Auto Finance, Enterprise Applications Transformation.

Experienced Global Manager with expertise in managing Business and Technical teams, vendors, and working with senior executive stakeholders. Motivated leader with extensive experience in large global IT transformations with high visibility

Skills

Product Management

Delivering the Product (functionality) from Inception to Delivery

Program and Delivery

Management

Managing the relationship of Offshore, Onsite and Client facing teams of the overall Program

Stakeholder Management

Building relationship with multiple internal and external stakeholders

API, Data Transformation

REST, Web Services, Data Modeling, FSDM, Data Migration, ETL Strategy

Agile Consulting

Distributed Agile Team Set up, Agile Coaching, Scrum

Application, Platform, Core

Banking Transformation

Complete Legacy Platform Migration and Redesign

Education

2003 – 2005 **MBA (Finance)**

Richmond, KY, Eastern Kentucky University

United States

1999 - 2002 Bachelors in Engineering (Electronics and Communication)

Chennai, TN, India HCE, University of Madras

Certificates

Employer Details

04/2022 - present

Amazon

Product Manager - Technical

02/2008 - 04/2022

Wipro Technologies - 2 Tower Center Blvd, NJ - 08816

Managing Consultant

Professional Experience - Projects and Clients

04/2022 - present

Product Manager - Technical

Amazon

- Managing and launching large, complex projects that span software development, operational changes in transportation and fulfillment centers, and business offering innovations
- Leading design and delivery of large /enterprise scale software systems across multiple teams/ organizations/ locations
- Working with multiple technology teams (including Amazon Business, Operations, and Prime) at Amazon to define priority business customer delivery experience scenarios and requirements
- Working with technology teams to build real time cost to serve projections to identify options for customers that save money for the customer and improve profitability for Amazon
- Representing Directors, Single Threaded Leaders in key stakeholder meetings, including at senior levels across the company
- Strong entrepreneurial orientation and general manager/ owner mentality a
 desire to build things from scratch and a willingness to roll up your sleeves and
 do whatever is necessary in an environment that is more start-up than big
 company
- Demonstrated analytical and quantitative skills; ability to use hard data and metrics to back up assumptions and develop financial business cases. Ability to clearly communicate data insights to others
- Demonstrated ability to dive deep in understanding the opportunity, our business, and the competitive landscape
- Create buy-in for the product/feature/service vision and strategy both internally and with key external partners
- Measure and analyze existing products for opportunities to innovate and improve, providing additional benefits to customers. Work closely with the product development team to define European customer product needs and get them prioritized for design and release

05/2016 - 04/2022 Mount Laurel, NJ

Managing Consultant (Technical Program/Product Manager)

TD Bank and Wipro Technologies

- Lead the Delivery of multiple Programs (Core Banking, API, and Microservices platform Transformation) serving clients in the wholesale and digital channels space.
- Develop a replacement strategy for aging legacy platforms with a new consolidated Omni-Channel platform
- Drive technology decision making during technology selection, buy vs build, technical architecture, design, and data migration
- Lead the Agile Transformation Program by sprint planning, creating epics and user stories with the help of JIRA using Agile-Scrum methodologies.

- Lead the SAFe transformation in Payments portfolio to align the Payments train with scaled agile principles for cost reduction, quality, and timely code deliveries
- Worked closely with staffing vendors to identify, interview, and bring strong technical talent on the teams
- Coach leaders and teams to organize around value address delays, and launch Agile Release Trains (ARTs)
- Drive Product prioritization, Requirements, Development, deployment execution with Engineering, and lead post-deployment support.
- Created a cohesive Strategy to ensure FSDM and Open API Framework Compliance. Built the path towards externalizing the APIs.
- Lead the Product and dev Team in working with multiple Middleware and API frameworks like IFX, Web services, REST, GraphQL
- Collaborate with the Product team on vision and strategy and keep teams up to date on your goals, timelines, and progress
- Lead, mentor, and Manage Product Management team serving in the US and India Geo.

02/2015 - 05/2016 Beaverton, OR

Managing Consultant (Technical Program/Product Manager)

Nike and Wipro Technologies

- Managed global team of 20+ resources including technology development engineers, testing leads, data leads, and business analysts.
- Provided strategic and tactical directions to the project sponsors and IT systems management by performing a gap analysis between existing and to be enhanced process flows, Return on Investment (ROI), Cost-benefit analysis and solution options including people, process, and technology.
- Collaborated with architecture team to drive proof of concept to adopt
 Microservices architecture first time in the business unit, participating in key
 technology decisions including service definition, technology selection,
 development approach, enabling organization to replace costly legacy
 infrastructure
- Leverage data to understand risks, impacts, scope and priorities of our business objectives, and enable the team to drive results.
- Led the Analytics Delivery team in Nike North America in the design of Analytics Dashboard, a unified Actuals vs Forecast of all the Business Lines of Nike at a given period of time.
- Created the design and delivery strategy in converting the data is sourced from various internal reports and external agencies into a consolidated online Dashboard that provides a point in time view of the Inventory and Financials of the various business lines.
- Work with business groups (Product, Software Development, Marketing, etc) to prioritize work (grounded in data) and improve the Viewer's Experience.
- Managed the offshore and Onsite Delivery of the Analytics Dashboard and the Enterprise Product Catalog Online Transformation Program from inception to delivery with the NALT Data Scientist, Onshore Business and the Offshore dev team.

01/2014 - 09/2014 Brisbane, Australia

Principal Consultant (Product Owner, Product Manager)

Suncorp Bank and Wipro Technologies

• Delivered the BPP (program) to replace the Bank's 16 core systems with five fully integrated systems powered by Oracle. The Banking Platform Program is all about simplification and delivering a scalable, robust, de-risked platform that supports the Bank's ongoing competitive position.

- Proactively identify meaningful process and infrastructure improvement opportunities and help own the product development process from discovery to release.
- Led Integration Strategy sessions with key business and technical stakeholders to determine the multiyear platform transformation schedule.
- Communicate performance metrics to key stakeholders throughout the organization
- Designed the Core Banking Consulting Roadmap from a Requirements and Analysis Perspective
- Led the Delivery of Custom development initiative in tandem with Oracle migration towards standalone products.
- Coached the team in Agile techniques, coordinated Quarterly PI Planning events and worked closely with teams and Release Train Engineers

09/2009 - 12/2013 Plano, TX

Principal Consultant (Product Owner, Product Manager), Agile Coach Capital One and Wipro Technologies

- Delivered the multiyear Data Transformation and Redesign Program through the stages of Data Complexity Reduction, Forklift, 3NF and completing with the establishment of Operational and Analytical Presentation Layer
- This initiative transformed the Organizations Data Environment from a patch work of Tables and Databases to a unified Teradata environment
- Managed the Delivery of the Auto Loan Sales Reporting Initiative detailing the revenue generated by the Dealerships. This initiative currently serves as the framework to deduce and align the Dealer incentives from an Analytical perspective.
- Established (Hands On) the Enterprise's first Distributed Agile Team(s) across the US and multiple cities in India
- Managed a team of Business Analysts, Developers and Data Modelers distributed across the US and India
- Played a decisive role in customizing the Teradata Design to fit the BI requirements of Capital One.
- Developed proof of concepts for removing legacy processes with the use of emerging technologies
- Worked with a team of Agile Coaches to design, develop, and execute strategies and supported practices to engage and influence stakeholders to make needed behavioral changes
- Mapped different business workflows in reference to multiple consuming channels from operational and Analytical perspectives

03/2009 - 09/2009 Denver, CO

Associate Consultant (Product Owner)

Dish Network and Wipro technologies

- Delivered the Enterprise Product Catalogue that contains the Organization wide
 Data structure constituted in an application consumable format. Enterprise
 Product Catalogue is a Framework of reference data that is created to serve as a
 common unified source (catalogue) to the Call center applications and the Web
 Based OE tools.
- Managed the delivery the SOA services candidates are designed to serve the Business purposes in conjunction with the IT capability in such a way that the availability of the Enterprise wide Data storage enhances the efficiency of the overall Business structure

02/2008 - 03/2009 Minneapolis, MN

Associate Consultant (Product Owner)

Target and Wipro Technologies

- Created the Prescriber and Prescription Modules of the Online Pharmacy Application to replace the legacy Application
- Interfaced with the Business and Technical teams in deducing the Strategic Approach towards the Pilot and Application Roll out.
- Delivered the Data Conversion program of the larger Pharmacy application development Project, the purpose of Data conversion is to provide a mechanism by which all required data (both operational and compliance) would be made available either in the required database for operational purposed or as an archive for Compliance related reasons.

Tools

- Teradata
- SQL
- VersionOne
- JIRA
- QT
- Tableau
- Oracle